So, all right, let's let's get to it.
All right, let's talk a little bit. We
have I know we'll get to as many of your
questions as possible.
Especially the super chats, we'll do all
of those.
Okay, so Trump says the economic costs
of the war are no big deal.
The price of oil
hit $120 a barrel, then it popped it
dropped down drooped down into the 80s
down of course from where it was it was
60 two weeks ago.
So
gas prices are already up over a dollar
25 cents a gallon nationally. Yeah.
>> Beginning of the war. I think I think
it's safe to say that the price per
barrel is going to go up
you know once the futures traders
realize that this is an ongoing thing
that Iranians aren't playing. This is
you know they they they tried playing
with us the first two two times and you
know third times not not going to
happen. Um
Trump says it's going to be a short-term
excursion cuz he's obviously trying to
calm the markets.
Um
What do you know?
>> No, it's not. Remember last week Ted we
said
what we have to do to win in Iran is we
have to overthrow the entire Iranian
government and impose a pro-American
pro-Israeli government in Tehran which
will never happen in a million years.
>> Nope. All the Iranians have to do to win
is to survive.
So either we're going to have to commit
to killing half of the people in Iran
over the next 20 years
or just walk away.
Which you and I both know what's going
to happen. Yeah. But it's going to take
a while, right? I mean now the Iranians
issued a statement yesterday saying you
know well we have a few surprises up our
sleeves too. I bet they do. I bet they
do too. Right? Hypersonic missiles,
anything else?
The hypersonics they have not yet used.
I think that the United States I think
the that the US and Israel have have
been taken by surprise with these
suicide drones. You know I I
researched this. These drones only cost
but five or six thousand dollars. That's
it. And you strap explosives to them,
which are also cheap. And then you just
fly them into an oil rig or into, you
know,
defense ministry building or into the
middle of an American
airbase or the control tower of an
airfield or
five grand. Yeah, easy peasy. Nothing
for a nation state. Yeah, our
surface-to-air missiles cost at least,
the small ones, at least a hundred and
fifty thousand dollars. We're spending a
hundred and fifty thousand dollars every
time we try to shoot down a five
thousand dollar drone. And it is
unsustainable. Besides the fact
that it's hard to shoot down these
drones and that's why so many of them
are impacting.
You know, all of the the six GCC
countries.
Let's talk a little bit about Bahrain.
So, Bahrain
it declared force majeure, which is a
legal term in contract law that says, we
are no longer able, you know, basically
in case of force majeure, we're no
longer able to honor our commitments
under this contract. They're saying we
can no longer supply energy as the state
Bahraini oil company said that they
could. That's a huge deal, right? Their
oil refinery
system is
>> Yeah. is crippled. Their ability to
transport oil is crippled.
>> Mhm. Um
if this goes on even a couple of weeks,
that's a major problem for a country
like that, isn't it? It's a major
problem for Bahrain, but it won't be a
major problem for the global economy
because Bahrain only produces about a
hundred thousand barrels a day. Mhm.
They consume about a hundred thousand
barrels a day, but the Saudis have
gifted Bahrain a small offshore oil
field
and that's the oil that they sell. Mhm.
>> So, it's it's like a little bit of a
a little bit of free money just to make
sure that the Bahrainis can keep up with
the rest of the Gulf Cooperation Council
countries.
Um
still
Bahrain relies on the income from this
offshore field. And if if there's force
majeure and they can't export it, which
they can't cuz for all intents and
purposes the the Strait of Hormuz is
closed right now.
Then it's going to
>> says like we're you know, we're going to
take it over. Yeah, good luck. What does
that mean?
>> how that works out.
Uh-huh. Yeah, okay. Just
basically. All right, we'll get to the
we're going to get to the the pack money
and the save act a little bit later, but
we have so many questions Sean. You okay
with us? Yeah, let's go for it. Adam's
Ark, thanks for the Emirati
dirhams for 50. Hey, if the US initiates
a ground invasion of Iran, do you think
missile and drone attacks on GCC
countries will stop? And if they do
invade, do you think IDF troops will
join them there? Seems only fair. Not
the second part.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, that's not the second Yeah, not
the second part. I mean ground troops in
my view ground troops would be the start
of World War III. I I really believe
that.
Plus you know, Iran
let's contextualize this. Iran is the
size of the whole of Western Europe.
That's true.
We can't invade and occupy a country
like that.
>> more rugged terrain. With more rugged
terrain than is than what is in Europe.
That's right. Yeah, you can't. You you
just can't. It's too big It's too big to
bite off. Um I don't think that No, I
think the missile and drone attacks
would only continue or accelerate.
>> I agree. Uh good morning Benjamin
Griffin. Love the show. Question I've
read reports from the IAEA that Iran has
enriched uranium up to 60%. Can you talk
a bit about what they claim the purpose
of this is? They they say it's for
nuclear energy.
In part and also for medical research.
Mhm.
Yeah, we which and that would be the
appropriate you know
uranium enrichment level for both of
those things.
Uh Sirous Devari, love your show. What
do you think of Mojtaba Khamenei, new
leader of the Islamic Republic? But
thanks for asking that question. Yeah.
Um
I don't think the only criticism is that
he's got the same last name as his dad.
You know, I think that just makes it you
know, it opens Iran up to the criticism
that they're basically setting up a
North Korean like hereditary system.
But I don't think John, I don't think
that's knowing what I know about
Iranians, I don't think I think this was
an act of defiance. I I like that. We're
going to choose someone that you guys
really don't want us to choose.
>> That is it. It's only because Donald
Trump said it's not going to be this guy
cuz I don't like him and I'm going to
choose the next leader of Iran. They
were like, oh yeah? And then they made
Mojtaba Khamenei Khamenei
uh Ayatollah. Yes.
>> have been compromising and compromising
and compromising and they're done. Yes.
That's it. That's it. That guy is he's
54 56 years old, but he's highly
respected from what I've I've been told.
Highly respected. Scott Holmes, what's
the status of Netanyahu?
I don't know what that means. Status.
Well, you know, Netanyahu ran off to
Germany to to hide when the war first
began. He's back in reportedly back in
Israel. I I read a report yesterday he's
he's actually in Cyprus. He's hiding is
what it comes down to.
Well,
>> I have to add one other thing. You know,
somebody posted a video on
on um
wherever Tik Tok last night that I
watched while I was laying in bed and it
was inside the Church of the Holy
Sepulchre which cuz was completely
empty. They're standing right next to
the Edicule which covers the tomb of
Christ and all you can hear are air raid
sirens. Wow. It was just very sad and
there's a lot of video coming out of
Israel where from
Israeli sources saying we're really in
trouble. They're hunkering down.
>> in trouble. They're not they're not
they're not dancing in the in the bomb
shelters.
>> No sir. No sir. You know, somebody
pointed out to me over the weekend too
that
you know, there was this
spike in support for Netanyahu when when
they first started bombing the Iranians,
it's back down to the point where his
popularity is nil. Yeah, maybe the
Iranians need to I mean the Israelis
need to stop thinking about like how
they feel about their own situation and
think about the situation that they're
creating all over the world which is
then coming back to bite them in the
ass.
Um That is right. Uh is there a
this war of escalation is there an end
game in sight Arnab wants to know. Uh
not in sight I think. Yeah, agreed. Um
Kuskovich hot take but I think if oil
shoots up high enough the US will lift
Russian oil sanctions and get oil from
them. Oh, there's conversations about
that. They already started that. They
already told the Indians, yeah, yeah, go
ahead and buy all the Russian oil you
want. Yeah, there's back channel
communications with the Russians right
now.
>> Yeah, there are. Absolutely. It's the
beginning the beginning of the end for
those sanctions. I would say timeline on
the oil sanctions is a week. What do you
think? I could see that. Want to support
the show with style? Go to
deprogram.live and check out our merch.
That's deprogram.live
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching.
Uh Maxwell Smart uh question for John
and Ted, if this
campaign was miraculously won, would the
US have enough control over the world's
oil supply to starve Russia and China?
That's a good question. I
The answer is no, I don't think.
>> No.
Um No, I don't think so.
I mean, it's it is a global market. It
is it is interesting, right? Like you
can be energy independent like the
Republicans were pushing for for years
and we are, but it doesn't make any
difference because it's [clears throat]
a global market. Mhm. So,
um anyway, um John Cusack, 10 bucks.
With Iran decapitated, Russia's
targeting Intel is the only way
the only strategic brain left guy
guiding IRGC strikes, is Moscow steering
a headless Iran to destroy GCC oil for
them.
Well, that's a tough one. I'm not sure I
would say Iran is decapitated yet,
either.
>> I I I don't think it is.
No, I don't think so.
Uh yeah, I don't know I don't want to
just like brush that
um
even
I don't know. I think I think Russia's
approach to Iran is more direct than
that. They're providing targeting
information. They're
they're an ally. They would do more if
they could. And I think it's basically
that simple. They're just honoring a
commitment. Um 3,500, I think these are
rupees or I don't know what they are.
Rishikesh, thank you so much. Um it
seems that the president's planning
victory by attrition, sparking a
revolution. Yeah, that is what he said
before. And a new US-friendly regime.
Does he really think we're going to
manage it successfully? Is there any
chance this will not result in a
complete disaster? It could result in a
partial disaster.
Yes, it could.
It's not going to work It's not going to
work.
>> It's not. It can't.
>> [music]
[music]